

# **Design & Web Development**

#### **Armando Salinas Elizondo**

Circón no 22, Pedregal de Atizapán, Atizapán de Zaragoza Estado de México.

55 5077 7296 / 55 6318 1718

Designer and web developer working on focused strategies to implement web environments like platforms for marketing and publicity using the newest technologies available on the internet.

# **Working Experience**

# **IECS (2022)**

Position: Web Analyst Sr.

Role / Tasks: Analyze the current web portal from the company and propose a new web platform

capable of satisfy the new needs of the company.

Achievements: Accomplish all the tasks needed to setup and release the new web platform from a list of

several option which included from built in software through inhouse alternatives, the final project was build using technologies such as html5, JavaScript and Angular on the

front end and Node JS on the backend side.

## Grupo Axo (2012 - 2020)

Position: Sr Web Developer & BI Analyst Jr.

Role / Tasks: Developing and maintaining several platforms used by the company, ELT developer

Achievements: Build a whole new extranet for internal use inside the company, redesign the company

corporate public website, team up with another IT areas in the processes to release a new ERP and being part of the team, which built the new Datawarehouse, BI reports

creation and ELT processes creator, Linux servers administrator.

# **Grupo Pochteca (2009 - 2012)**

Position: Webmaster Sr, Intranet / Extranet / social media

Role / Tasks: Build and maintain several sites and micro site from the companies' different brands,

email marketing management and deployment.

Achievements: Redesign and deploy multiple sites for the company using adobe coldfusion, support to another latam countries, support to other areas from the company building newsletter

campaigns for the merchandise and IT areas.

# Inmobiliaria Gicsa (2006 – 2009)

Position: Webmaster

Role / Tasks: Manage and develop new modules for the corporate website and for latin America

websites including and Extranet.

Achievements: Design a new corporate website including new features which included support for customers, creation and deployment of new tools for the management of the brokers like

a CRM and a Extranet.

# **Training**

#### Visio 5

Place: Miami Florida (1999)

Description: 4 days training for Microsoft Visio.

### Onmark 2000

Place: Atlanta Georgia (1999)

Description: Training for Onmark 2000 analyze tools.

### Desarrollando Visio 2000

Place: México D.F (1999)

 $Description: \quad Entrenamiento\ para\ software\ diagram ador.$ 

# Queryng Microsoft SQL Server 2000 with Transact - SQL

Place: México D.F. (2002)

Description: Introduction to queryng Microsoft SQL Server.

#### Introduction to a ASP

Place: México D.F. (2002)

Description: Server side scripting with ASP

# **Developing managment skills**

Place: México D.F ITESM (2004)

Description: none.

# **Sharepoint 2007**

Place: México D.F. (2008)

Description: Introduction to the usage and deployment of Sharepoint solutions.

### **Visual Studio 2008**

Place: Miami Florida (2009)

Description: none.

#### **Skills**

# Serverside Scripting Languages:

Javascript, Php, Asp, Coldfusion, Java, Python.

#### **Frameworks**

Node Js, Express, React Js.

## Markup and structured languages

HTML, XML, JSON, CSS, Saas, Type Script

# **Business Intelligence**

Microsoft Reporting Services, Micorosoft Integration Service, Pentaho, Talend Open Studio.

# Free Software & framewroks

Wordpress, Joomla, OsCommerce, Moodle, vTiger CRM, and SugarCRM.

### **Database Engines**

MSSQLSEVER, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MariaDB, MongoDB

#### Web Servers

IIS 7-8, Apache 1.8 – 2.2, Nginx (básico).

### Servers

Windows 2000-2012 Server, Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Fedora.

## About me

My experience as a web designer and developer have allowed me to understand each of the steps that is needed to implement any type of website, this involves from the initial information and steps on the interface through the implementation and start-up of the final release, going through each of the necessary steps for its proper implementation, I have participated in projects where I have built web sites from the graphic part to the interaction with data from some type of repository (Frontend and Backend), as well as in the implementation of security standards in case of that apply. Proven experience in the Business Intelligence area, including report creation and interface development, connection between systems, API development.

### **Academic Information**

# **Bachelor Degree Graphic Design**

Universidad del Valle de México Campus Lomas Verdes Estado de México. 1993 - 1996.

# **Master Degree MBA**

Universidad del Valle de México Campus Lomas Verdes Estado de México.

# Languages

### Languages

Spanish: Native

inglés: Intermediate writing, listening and speaking..